

DENNIS GALVÉN

Senior iOS-& Android Engineer

DETAILS

Helsingborg, Sweden dennis.galven@pm.me +46736719163

PROFILE

Hey there! I'm a Senior Mobile Engineer with over 6 years of experience building awesome mobile apps. I'm comfortable working with both iOS and Android platforms and can write code in native and Flutter development. My expertise also includes developing backend systems with GCP. One of my favorite things about being a senior engineer is getting to share my knowledge with junior developers and helping them grow their skills. When I'm not coding up a storm, I love to unwind by playing hockey or diving into video games. And yeah, I have a bit of a habit of taking apart tech just for fun (even if I can't always put it back together).

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior iOS & Android Engineer, Strafe, Consultant, Stockholm

FEBRUARY 2023

The app:

E-sport news and content

Tasks:

Bring two old code bases up to date

Feature development

Maintenance

CI/CD Setup for both Android and iOS

Flutter Engineer, OhCleo, Consultant, Stockholm

JANUARY 2023

Helped them to get their code base on the right track. They had some very severe performance issues. Mapped out an app architecture and started the work while coaching their Junior dev on how to move forward.

Senior iOS Engineer, Hemnet, Consultant, Stockholm

AUGUST 2022 - JANUARY 2023

The App:

Housing market app. Biggest app for buying and selling property in Sweden.

Tasks:

Refactoring objective-c to Swift
Refactoring the UI from UIKit/Story boards to SwiftUI

Maintenance and bug fixing Development of new features

Extras:

Coached and mentored junior developers

Senior iOS Engineer, Spiideo, Consultant, Malmö

JANUARY 2022 - AUGUST 2022

The App:

Sports analysis tool. Together with permanently installed cameras or portable cameras, the app can, with the help of Machine Learning, keep track of where all participants on the field are Through AR, the user cankeep track of, for example, how far a player has run, distance to nearest opponent, distance between fellow players, etc. Used by Major clubs in football throughout the world. Allsvenskan and SHL also use these tools. To name a few.

Tasks:

Refactoring the UI from UIKit to SwiftUI

Moved dependencies from Pods to Swift Package Manager Set up CI/CD with Mac Minis and Gitlab CI Maintenance and bug fixing

Integration between camera hardware, router hardware and the iOS app

Senior iOS, Android & Devops Engineer, Collector Bank, Consultant, Göterborg

SEPTEMBER 2021 - JANUARY 2022

The App:

Walley is the name and it's a Klarna competitor. An app where you can see and pay your invoices, installments, create installment plans, connect bank transfers and receive reminders, etc

Tasks:

Further development/Maintenance of iOS & Android app

Rewrote the app as a flutter prototype Made an integration between the app, Slack, Google sheets & customer service via Google Cloud Platform

CI/CD setup

Google Optimize setup on the web app so it can run A/B tests

iOS Engineer, IKEA IT AB, Helsingborg

JANUARY 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2021

The App:

IKEA e-commerce. The user can shop online, click & collect, be inspired, scan goods in the store, manage family memberships, etc.

Around 10 million daily active users

Tasks:

Maintenance & Bug fixing

Wrote the implementation that enables the user to scan and pay goods in the stores with the app Manage dependencies between the teams within IKEA IT Set up CI/CD with Github actions.

Extras:

Interim iOS Lead Developer

Lead iOS & Android Engineer, Playtech BGT Sports, Malmö

SEPTEMBER 2018 - JANUARY 2020

The apps:

Ladbrokes betting app

White label solution that betting companies could order and have deployed within 48 hours. All betting interfaces were wrapped in a web view so the betting company could use their current sportsbook.

Tasks:

Maintenance & BugFixing in Ladbrokes iOS & Android app

Developed a white label betting app Developed a 3D football/soccer penalty shootout game

iOS Engineer, Tactel/Swedbank, Malmö

JUNE 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2018

Objective-C heavy iOS feature development

iOS & Android Engineer, Wellbefy, Helsingborg

JANUARY 2018 - JUNE 2018

Prototyping iOS and Android apps

EDUCATION

Mobile app development, Malmö Yrkeshögskola, Malmö

JANUARY 2017 - JANUARY 2018

Music Production, Växjö University, Växjö

JUNE 2006 - JUNE 2008

LINKS

LinkedIn Github

SKILLS

iOS Development Android Development

Backend Development Flutter

Firebase Google Cloud Platform

Swift Kotlin

Dart JavaScript

TypeScript Git
GitHub JIRA
Gitlab Gerrit

Bitbucket

LANGUAGES

Swedish English